I've got news on the brain organoids you
know the tiny human brains we grow from
stem cells we already knew they could do
some pretty spooky things like take over
the body and be able to use the muscles
of a decapitated Mouse and we knew that
we could insert them into damaged areas
of the brain and they would take over
that role and they are indeed functional
when placed into the brain of a rat it
does fully integrate with the rat
neurons these researchers wanted to know
if they could take a brain organoid and
if it could replace the sick brain
of a rat researchers genetically
engineered rats to have something called
Timothy syndrome this is a rare
autosomal dominant condition that can be
passed from parent Offspring and can
also come from spontaneous mutation it
can be mild but it can also be severe it
causes cognitive defects and a lot of
problems with how the neurons function
they then took the rat's own stem cells
and genetically edited them to not have
Timothy syndrome they then grew brain
organoids and implanted it into the
rat's brain not only did it functionally
integrate but it also started to replace
areas of the brain that didn't work
essentially it took over this leads to a
lot of questions like is it really you
so if you had something like a stroke
and had a damaged area of your brain and
you used your own stem cells to make a
foreign brain and insert it into yours
and it took over at one point does it
become not you we know that identical
twins may have the same genes but they
are very unique and individual I think
once we start moving this into human
trials it's going to get really weird